Finding Aid for the Ferdinand Praeger Collection of Scores, circa 1829-1891
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Keyboard works, 1837-1891, I.; Item 001-369
  - Piano, 1837-1891, A.; Item 001-332
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 21, A 21st sonata in A / 1889, 21 p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Twenty-first sonata in A Additional title in caption: Symphony in A no. 2 Caption title on p. 9: 2nd symphony in A (Box 6, Item 300)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 1, 15, 21. Caption on p. 3: 12 July 89; caption on p. 9: 12 July 89; caption on p. 15: 11 Aug. 89; margin on p. 21: Aug. 22 89. Work begins in A minor, ends in A major.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 22, A Sonata no. 22 in A / 1889, 17 p. of ms. music; 36 cm.; At head of title page: Symphony in A no. 1 (Box 6, Item 301)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 3, 5, 12. Caption on p. 6: 7 July 1889. Work begins in A minor, ends in A major.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 23, C minor 23rd sonata in C minor / 1888, 11 p. of ms. music; 32 cm.; Alternate title: Twenty-third sonata in C minor (Box 6, Item 302)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout Caption: 13 Sept. 88; margin of p. 5: 17 Sept. 88.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 24, C 24th sonata in C / 1886, 9 p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Twenty-fourth sonata in C (Box 6, Item 303)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Margin of p. 1: 21 Nov. 1886. Work begins in C minor, ends in C major.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 25, G 25th sonata in G / [18--], 13 p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Twenty-fifth sonata in G (Box 6, Item 304)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 6, 12. Margin of p. 8: Sept. 10. Work begins in G minor, ends in G major.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 26, G minor 26th sonata for piano in G minor / 1889, 16 p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Twenty-sixth sonata for piano in G minor (Box 7, Item 305)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout. Cover: Sept 1889; caption of p. 11: 1 May 1889.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 27, F Sonata no. 27 / 1889, 18 p. of ms. music; 31-35 cm.; Alternate title: Additional title in caption: Symphony in F (Box 7, Item 306)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout. Caption: 2 July 89. Work begins in F minor, ends in F major.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 28, C 28th sonata for piano in C / 1890, 8 p. of ms. music; 38 cm. (Box 7, Item 307)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 8. Cover: May 1890; caption on p. 1: 16/5 90; caption on p. 2: 13/5 90; caption on p. 6: 15/4 90; caption on p. 7: 18/5 90. Work begins in C minor, ends in C major.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 29, C major 29th sonata or symphony in C / 1890, 15 p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Twenty-ninth sonata or symphony in C (Box 7, Item 308)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. 10. Cover: 22 June 1890; caption of p. 6: 21 June 90.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 30, C major 30th Sonata in C / [ca. 1890], [20] p. of ms. music; 35 cm.; Alternate title: Thirtieth sonata in C (Box 7, Item 309)
      For piano. Cover title. Manuscript (Ink).
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 31, G minor Thirty-first sonata for piano / 1890, [13] p. of ms. music; 31-38 cm. (Box 7, Item 310)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). P. 2-7 are 31 cm., all other pages are 38 cm. Cover: 1890; margin of p. 8: 20/4 90.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 35, C major 35th sonata for piano in C / 1891, [16] p. of ms. music; 32 cm.; Alternate title: Thirty-fifth sonata for piano in C (Box 7, Item 311)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. [5]. Caption: 1891; caption on p. [7]: May 1891; margin of p. [15]: 12.3.91; caption of p. [16]: 11.3.91.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatinas, piano, no. 1, A minor Sonatina no. 1 in A minor / [1889?], 4 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 312)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). "Dedicated to Miss Marie Hecht"--Caption. Published by E. Donajowski, London, 1889. Additional markings on p. 1 in blue pencil and ink, including "Donaj".
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatinas, piano, no. 2, C major Sonatina no. 2 in C major / [1889?], 5 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 313)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink), with additional markings in blue pencil and ink. "Dedicated to Master Henry Hecht"--Caption. Published by E. Donajowski, London, 1889.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatinas, piano, no. 3, E♭ major Sonatina no. 3 in E♭ major / [1889?], 5 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 314)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink), with additional markings in blue pencil and ink. "Dedicated to his daughter Mrs. J. Edwards"--Caption. Published by E. Donajowski, London, 1889.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Le songe / [18--], [5] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 315)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink), with additional markings in pencil. Incomplete work.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Spanish dance = Danse espagnole / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Danse espagnole (Box 7, Item 316)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Stormy night / [18--], [1] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 317)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Stürm march / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 32 cm. (Box 7, Item 318)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink), with additional markings in pencil. Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1, 2, 4].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Te souviens tu?: romance pour piano / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 319)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Thema mit sechs Veränderungen = Tema con variazioni / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Tema con variazioni (Box 7, Item 320)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Tempo di mazurka / 1838, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 321)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: July 12 1838; p. [1] margin: 14 July; July 1838.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 La tentation: grande valse, piano / [18--], [5] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 322)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1-3].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Valse-rhapsodie / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 7, Item 323)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Volkslied, piano, C minor Volkslied [in C minor] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 324)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Volkslied, piano, G major Volkslied [in G major] / 1891, [1] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 325)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Incomplete work. "The very last piece written by Ferdinand Praeger after which he took to what proved to be his death bed, Leonie Praeger."--left margin.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Volkslied, piano, G minor Volkslied [in G minor] / 1837, [1] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 326)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 1837; margin: copied from an old M.S.[?].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Waltzes, piano, F major Waltz / 1890, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 327)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 16/12. 90, Missie's birthday 17/12.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Walzer rhapsodie, piano, A♭ major Walzer rhapsodie [in A flat major] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 7, Item 328)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Walzer rhapsodie, piano, E♭ major Walzer rhapsodie [in E flat major] / 1877, 5 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 329)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 21 January 1877.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 [Untitled work for piano in A flat major] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 330)
      For piano. Title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. [1]. Caption information indecipherable.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 [Untitled work for piano in G major] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 29 cm. (Box 7, Item 331)
      For piano. Indecipherable title in caption; title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Ink).
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Piano music. Selections [Four works for piano] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 7, Item 332)
      For piano. Title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Ink).
      Contents: Maestoso -- Andante -- Maestoso -- Hymn.
  - Piano four hands, undated, B.; Item 333-334
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Das Hühnengrab: symphonische Dichtung, vierhändig piano / [18--], 8 p. of ms. music; 36 cm. (Box 7, Item 333)
      For piano four hands. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout. Primo and secondo parts on facing pages.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Undine: piano vierhändig / [18--], 4 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 334)
      For piano four hands. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 4. Primo and secondo parts on facing pages.
  - Organ, 1882-1891, C.; Item 335-341
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Gloriosa / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 335)
      For keyboard instrument, possibly organ. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1, 3].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Lamentation, keyboard instrument, A minor Lamentation!; Jolly life; Nocturne / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 29 cm.; Alternate title: Jolly life Alternate title: Nocturne (Box 7, Item 336)
      For keyboard instrument, possibly harmonium. Caption title. Holograph (Ink), with additional sketches in pencil. Only the first title is complete.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nearer to death, nearer to peace! / 1891, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 337)
      For keyboard instrument, possibly harmonium. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 7/3 1891.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, organ Organ sonata / 1882, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 7, Item 338)
      For organ. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Incomplete work. Caption: 7 Sept. 1882.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Voluntaries, organ. Selections 16 voluntaries for harmonium or organ / [18--], [30] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Sixteen voluntaries for harmonium or organ (Box 7, Item 339)
      For harmonium or organ. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. [21].
      Contents: No. 1: Moderato [G major] -- No. 2: Moderately fast [C major] -- No. 3: Slowly [D minor] -- No. 4: Slowly [E♭ major] -- No. 5: Very moderate [C major] -- No. 6: Rather fast [C major] -- No. 7: Andante [F major] -- No. 8: Moderato [G major] -- No. 9: Molto lento [G major] -- No. 10: Andantino [E♭ major] -- No. 11: Allegro moderato [G major] -- No. 12: Andante [G major] -- No. 13: Allegro moderato [F major] -- No. 14: Lento [F major] -- No. 15: Pastorale [C major] -- No. 16: Allegretto scherzando [C major].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Voluntaries, organ. Selections 40 voluntaries / [18--], [32] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Forty voluntaries (Box 7, Item 340)
      For organ. Caption title. Holograph (Ink).
      Contents: No. 1: Lento [F major] -- No. 2: [F major] -- No. 3: Moderato [G major] -- No. 4: [A major] -- No. 5: Andantino [D major] -- No. 6: Moderato [E minor] -- No. 7: Allegro moderato [F major] -- No. 8: Molto lento [E major] -- No. 9: Adagio [G major] -- No. 10: Moderato [G major] -- No. 11: [G major] -- No. 12: Moderato [B♭ major] -- No. 13: Lento [B minor] -- No. 14: [B minor] -- No. 15: Moderato [A♭ major] -- No. 16: Lento [G major] -- No. 17: Andante [G major] -- No. 18: Moderato [C major] -- No. 19: Adagio [G major] -- No. 20: Molto moderato [E minor] -- No. 21: Lento [C major] -- No. 22: Maestoso [C major] -- No. 23: [C major] -- No. 24: Andantino [D major] -- No. 25: Molto lento [A minor] -- No. 26: Hymn [F major] -- No. 27: Hymn [G minor] -- No. 28: Andantino [E♭ major] -- No. 29: Moderato [E♭ major] -- No. 30: [A minor] -- No. 31: Lento [G major] -- No. 32: Andantino [F major] -- No. 33: Andante [C major] -- No. 34: Moderato [C major] -- No. 35: Andante [F major] -- No. 36: Adagio [A♭ major] -- No. 37: Adagio [G major] -- No. 38: Andante [F major] -- No. 39: Andante [A♭ major] -- No. 40: [E♭ major].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Keyboard instrument music. Selections [Three untitled works for keyboard instrument / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 7, Item 341)
      For keyboard instrument, possibly organ. Title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Ink). The works have been numbered 128, 129, 130 in pencil in the margin.
      Contents: 128: Andante religioso -- 129: Allegro Maestoso -- 130: [no marking].
  - Piano reductions, 1853-1890, D.; Item 342-370
    It is unclear why some of these works were identified as piano scores of works for a larger ensemble, and how it was determined whether this ensemble was an orchestra or a wind band. Only some of the pieces in this category have specific markings that indicate that they were intended for a larger ensemble. Some have notes that state that they were to be scored for orchestra, wind instruments, or strings, while others only have instrument names noted above the staff at a few points in the score. Many have no markings at all, so we cannot be certain that they are indeed piano scores of larger works.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Adagios, piano, C major (1890) Adagio [in C major], 1890, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 342)
      For piano. Title from initial tempo marking. Holograph (Ink). Caption: To be scored for strings. Caption: 6/12 90.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Allegro feroce, piano, C minor Allegro feroce / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 30 cm. (Box 8, Item 343)
      For piano. Title from initial tempo-expression marking. Holograph (Ink). Incomplete work. Possibly intended to be orchestrated for band; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of a band work. Caption: E. Maude Quirke. 52 York Road W. Brighton.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Andantes, piano, G major Andante [in G major] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 344)
      For piano. Title from initial tempo marking. Holograph (Ink). Caption: Scored for wind instruments.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Bayadère, piano, B♭ major La bayadère / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 32 cm. (Box 8, Item 345)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). At bottom of page: für Violin & Piano zu arrangieren. Possibly intended to be scored for violin and piano. Corrections on inserts pasted throughout.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Bridal Procession / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 8, Item 346)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). At head of title: No. 8. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Chor & Zug / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 30 cm.; Alternate title: Chor und Zug (Box 8, Item 347)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Incomplete work. Possibly intended to be orchestrated for band; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of a band work.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Concerto, violin, orchestra; arr. Concerto for violin / 1882, 2 ms. piano scores ([2] p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Item 348)
      Score in piano format, presumably intended to be orchestrated. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Second score includes line for solo violin. Incomplete work. Caption of piano score: 1 April 1882; Caption of violin and piano score: 2 April, 1882.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Elegies, piano, G minor Elegy / 1853, [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 349)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Incomplete work. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. Caption: 1853. Last system on p. [1] marked "Oboi", "Flauti", and "Fagott".
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Fest Aufzug: ernster Marsch / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 28 cm.; Alternate title: Ernster Marsch (Box 8, Item 350)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: No. 1. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Festival march / [18--], [1] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 8, Item 351)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1]. Following title: No. 15. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory. Another copy in collection titled Bridal procession march.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Festival march Bridal procession march / [18--], [1] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 8, Item 352)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). In caption "No. 12" crossed out, changed to 15. Caption: 2nd copy. Another copy in collection titled Festival march. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Funeral march of Hans Sachs / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 353)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [2]. Following title: No. 4. Top of p. [2]: Chorus of maidens strewing flowers. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Grande marche, C major Grande marche [in] C [major] / 1879, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 354)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1-2]. Caption: 27/9 1879. At head of title: No. 2. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Grande marche, C minor Grande marche in C minor / [18--], [5] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Marcia (Box 8, Item 355)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout; loose inserts in envelope. At head of title: No. 14. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Hussitenpredigt = Introduction to The Hussites / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Introduction to the Hussites Alternate title: Hussites (Box 8, Item 356)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Hymne patriotique / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 8, Item 357)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Following title: No. 9. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Idylle, piano, C major Idylle [in C major] / 1889, 5 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 358)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 2 June 89. Caption: Scored for wind inst.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Introduction, piano, D minor Introduzione [in D minor] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 8, Item 359)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Introduction et scherzo, piano, C major Introduction et scherzo / 1889, 6 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 360)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 1. Caption: 31 May 89; end of second system: 2 June. Cover: Scored for wind inst.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Jubilee march, piano Jubilee march / 1887, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: March: piano (Box 8, Item 361)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 1887. Bottom of pages torn from left edge to center. "Composed for and performed by the Band of the Grenadier Guards conducted by Dan Godfrey Esqr."--Cover. Probably composed in honor of the 50th anniversary celebration of Queen Victoria's reign.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. King Lear / [18--], [6] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 362)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Page numbering omits page 3. Incomplete work. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. Second system on p. [5] marked "celli & contrabassi unisons".
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Marche hongroise / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Title on accompanying label: Hungarian march in A (Box 8, Item 363)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1-3]. At head of title: No. 6. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Marche Turque / [18--], 8 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 364)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout. Following title: No. 11. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Marches, piano, D minor Marche / 1888, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 365)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Possibly intended to be orchestrated for band; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of a band work. Caption: 30 Nov 88.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Marches, piano, F major Marcia / [18--], [5] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 366)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1, 4, 5]. Following title: No. 10. Possibly intended to be orchestrated; listed in Finkelman's Ferdinand Praeger Archive Inventory as a piano score of an orchestra work. One in a sequence of 15 numbered marches in the Finkelman inventory.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891. Trauermarsch, C minor Trauermarsch: [in C minor] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 8, Item 367)